hey everyone thank you for listening to
The Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Dar mikowski this podcast I talk about
ways to grow your coaching and online
course business to get more clients to
make more money now today I want to talk
about how do you actually promote your
business promote your offers and attract
new clients brand new people that you've
never talked to that you've never met
before to your offers and to your
business let's say that you have an
offer that you're putting out there you
got your lead magnet created and you're
ready to promote it you got your
coaching program built out this is going
to assume that you have all that stuff
ready to go ready to promote you got
something that's ready for people to
sign up for okay if you don't have that
we have a ton of training that we've
been putting out on my YouTube channel
all about everything that leads up to
that point okay in my coaching program
the client growth accelerator we have a
lot of training that breaks down what to
do after that point and that's what we
work with people on every single week is
how do we scale their businesses to be
able to make six and seven figures I
want to break down for you in this
episode what you need to do once you got
your offer ready to
go to promote your offer you got to get
it in front of the people that want it
okay duh of course but like how do you
find those people and so the number one
way that most people do is they're going
to put it on their social media they're
going to send it to their email list and
if you don't have a big email list
they're just going to be doing their
social media here's what ends up
happening for most people is they spend
a bunch of time
a lot of time building their offer
together and they put it out there on
social media nobody signs up that's what
happens for most people um and and then
they get frustrated and they're like
online marketing doesn't work this whole
thing doesn't work it's a scam it's it's
a waste of time that's not true it's
just the fact is that the algorithms
literally are designed to deprioritize
content that coaches mentors and course
creators do um and so there's there
there's not anything that you did wrong
on this it's just that when you have
something of value like that to put out
there the algorithms
prioritize content that is entertainment
that's going to be engaging that grabs
people's attention it doesn't prioritize
information it doesn't prioritize things
that change people's lives and and so
unfortunately if that's what we're
putting out is content like that it's
not going to do very much for us now
when you have people in your ecosystem
there's a flywheel that ends up
happening flywheel effect is basically
this idea that you can take the way a
flywheel works on a car is that there's
a weighted wheel that keeps momentum
going and so that's what exactly what a
flywheel effect is is that content based
social media content helps the flywheel
go as you have more people on there okay
so again if you're like just pounding
your head trying to get people on your
social media trying to people or
organically that way nine times out of
10 not very many people are going to
sign up so you're going to have to
really think outside of the box in that
the the best way if you don't have any
money to spend on ads to think outside
the box you have to literally reach out
to people
Cod write them DM them um message them
and spark up conversations is what you
have to do and so you have to like
contact people that maybe you have
engaged with them before see where
they're at in their business see what's
going on with them see where they're at
in their life see what if it's related
to what you do in your business and then
you start sending them pieces of content
that you put together on your social
media and that starts to Prime the
flywheel and get it going okay so you
got to actually engage with other people
rather than just I put content out there
and it draws people to me all right
so you got to be active at actually
putting yourself in front of the right
people
and the truth is is that if you are
dming people to do that most of the
people that you're going to direct
message are not going to be a good fit
they're not going to want anything to do
with what you're talking about you're
going to you're going to annoy a lot of
people uh but if you can become okay
with that if you're okay with and and by
the way I would recommend to become 100%
comfortable with irritating people with
not worrying what other people think
about you to grow your business
100% um if you don't want to do that now
what are the options that we have to
market right so those are our free
options YouTube is a great option and so
YouTube is one option because it does it
is one of the last um organic pieces
that's out there that you can put
content on there but I'm talking like
you're going to have to record couple of
times a week 30 to 40 minute videos that
are really indepth that teach something
and then attached to every one of those
videos you want to have some kind of an
offer or a lead Magnet or something that
you're drawing people into again that's
going to be a trickle of people that
takes a long time to get that flywheel
going so all of the ways that we do it
for free to promote again for most
coaches and
mentors it's uh it's it's going to be
crickets it's going to be very few
people are going to sign up for anything
that you do and and again that can be
frustrating now you can make a business
work by doing that but here's what I
recommend there's really two of the best
ways to grow your business number one is
if you know of
somebody who you can partner with who
you can be on their platform you can
talk to their audience and then by doing
so you're able to promote your social
media your content your training and you
might even have a JV deal where they get
some of your content just for signing up
and buying something from somebody else
I've done that before and that actually
led to quite a few clients that way for
me because people saw my content that I
did on somebody else's
platform and then came came over to mine
okay now the and and by the way that's
actually very effective it really is
because you're able to borrow the trust
from somebody else by joining their
platform by you know maybe some of the
people who follow them may be interested
in what you offer or what you're doing
and so again this is why networking this
goes back to being intentional to
connect
with where are the people that are going
to buy from me who are those people you
get into
conversations to create
connection with the people that are
going to bring business to you overall
okay so I had I had to do that in the
beginning and a lot of times it was it
was actually clients that I was working
with doing what I do in my business it
was people that I actively went out
there and found and then I helped them
get a lot of a result and then they
helped promote me in the beginning by
doing that okay but that can be a lot of
work the easiest way and again a lot of
L of people they don't like this but
it's literally is one of the easiest and
you have the most control over it and if
you follow the system that we teach I
have a free training that I put together
about this um that you can watch is
running paid advertising Facebook and
Instagram ads and before you shut off
this training I want you to just
understand why this is one of the best
ways to actually promote your business
because you have control over who it
goes in front of a lot of control over
that you have control over
when people are going to show up with
you and you can increase how many people
are going to connect with you by adding
more budget to your advertising campaign
now this is why if your offer isn't
dialed in your ads are going to go to
zero if your language isn't dialed in if
your sales copy isn't dialed in because
the way the ads work is they actually
use the language that you write to
decide who do they put it in front of
and so that those words that you use you
want those to hyper strongly qualify
slash disqualify you want to qualify the
right people and by automatically doing
that you're going to automatically
disqualify who is not a good fit for you
and so what does that fall in the
category of when you're running a paid
ads
campaign who is disqualified as somebody
who is not probably going to buy from
you they might be interested in what you
offer but they're not going to purchase
from you
and so this is one of the things that I
that I do and this is why everything
that I teach comes from this angle of
direct response marketing because it's
also based on the same flywheel effect
so every piece of content that I put out
there comes from an advertising first
Focus who am I marketing to first I'm
hyper focused on the type of person that
I want to bring in because if I bring
them in through an ad now I want them
engaging with other pieces of content
that I put out there and this is where
organic helps amplify
what you're doing with your advertising
campaigns because if you advertise to
people chances
are and and this is the harsh reality
that you got to understand is you can
put out a great offer you can have that
you can have a great webinar sales
process and
yet uh very few small percentage of
those people are actually going to
become clients of yours in one outing in
one offer in one sitting and so the way
that we actually let's say you pulled a
bunch of people onto your email list you
or they watched a presentation with you
is you continue to engage with them with
additional pieces of content with
additional presentations with additional
connect points where you're connecting
with the same person again and again and
again until they either decide they
don't want anything to do with you or
they end up becoming a client and that's
where that flywheel effect starts to
come into place is if I'm not putting
out organic content my ads actually
don't perform as well long in the big
picture because with the advertising
campaigns I'm going to pull somebody
into my ecosystem onto my email list for
some kind of an offer a very specific
offer a presentation and now I'm going
to continue if they like me they're
going to be following me on my social
media I'm going to make sure of that
they're going to be watching all the
content that I put out there they're
going to
be they're going to DM me first first
and now I've started a conversation with
somebody by them dming me instead of me
actively going out there and cold dming
so now it turns away from a numbers game
of me trying to cold attract people and
it turns
into this these are qualified people
that are in my inbox that I'm chatting
with that I'm talking to that I'm
engaging with they're qualified for what
I have to offer and they're looking for
the thing that I'm promoting
okay and so actively this now becomes a
part of our system a part of our
ecosystem and they're and they're in my
world and when they come in through an
ads campaign I'm targeting the right
person they're not they might not buy
from me right away but as they continue
to engage with me then they will and so
this is why again a lead magnet to some
kind of a pre-recorded webinar or video
training uh is going to going to be one
of the very best formats of offers that
you can put out there especially when it
comes to your time Freedom Live Events
is one of the very best offers that you
can put out there a live webinar a a
three-day challenge five-day
challenge these are all great offers um
if you do a live event there's a little
bit of that factor of you got to show up
live if you do it pre-recorded you might
have a little bit of a lower percentage
convert uh but it's a great balance long
term if you get the flywheel working and
so that's why like I've transitioned my
whole business over to Evergreen because
the flywheel is able to work and I got
those things spinning over and over and
over again getting people into my
ecosystem from multiple touch points
every piece of content that I put out
there is towards engaging with the right
people to bring them into my coaching
program to bring them into my client
growth accelerator program because if
you're watching any piece of content of
mine and maybe you're listening to this
right
now you're the type of person who uh is
going to be a great fit for what we we
work with you with in our accelerator
program where we help you dial In Those
ads campaigns where we help you dial in
what do you actually say in your offer
your landing pages how do you structure
your Evergreen uh trainings how do you
put together those promotion offers
those vsls all of that stuff we go
through all that with you we give you
scripts and templates and all the things
to say and what to do in there so you
don't have to think about it you just
follow the system and the system works
for you and so that's what we're looking
looking for is people that will jump in
with us that are qualified for what we
have to offer and and and and it's funny
I even just now put in a a small
infomercial into my podcast about my
coaching program the client growth
accelerator the last two minutes what
I've been talking about is literally
like an infomercial for my accelerator
program but it's also a direct example
to you of how you need to be promoting
your business constantly promoting to
people letting them know what you have
to offer what you're trying to um
address with them and so again if you
want to know how to run paid ads
campaigns we have a training that I just
released all about what's the best way
to create Facebook ads you got to again
have a landing page you got to have your
sales copy dialed in you got to have
your ads copy the language that you say
dialed in it doesn't take a lot to do
that we use AI to help us do a lot of
that a lot of the the AI prompts that we
put together our chat jpt prompt
document helps us do that as well okay
and so again when it comes to promoting
your business there's a lot of different
ways to promote it um I'll say this for
coaches and course creaders SEO is
pretty much dead it really is um because
there's so many different people that
are out there and now even with AI like
SEO is again starting to Fall by the
wayside and but paid advertising is
picking up YouTube is still a great
resource
um there's a formula for what to say on
your YouTube videos there is a formula
for what type of content gets engagement
but a lot of times like you got to
really know who are you talking to you
got to know what grabs their attention
the most and then talk through that and
talk in that way and so again my YouTube
channel we've actually had some great
traction with it um great traction I
consider on a YouTube channel you got a
couple 100 organic views whenever you
put out a YouTube video I love that like
we're able to get that on our YouTube
video I I could barely get like 10 views
on my YouTube videos a year and a half
ago two years ago so the fact that we're
getting a couple hundred now on average
with a lot of our YouTube videos is
exciting because it shows that we're
gaining that momentum we're keeping
people engaged through the content
they're watching the content I see the
analytics of how many people are
watching through our content that we're
putting out there so again that's a
great resource YouTube is a great
valuable resource in conjunction with
your ads campaigns in conjunction with
your email list all of it works together
it's a system it's an ecosystem trying
to just use one piece so I'm going to
put content out there and hope people
signs up that is going to be the
lowest bottom of the
barrel fewest people that you're going
to get overall and and for most people
that's why they give
up and and truly I actually think that
if they just ran some simple ads
campaigns like we teach in my program uh
they wouldn't give up because they would
start to see the results like our
clients do and they would start to see
real results and and paid clients start
to come in with them all right so again
I'd love to work with you in my
accelerator program love to have you
join us as a part of that uh listen if
this episode has helped you share it
with somebody don't hold it just to
yourself grow your love to everybody
talk soon have a
[Music]
[Applause]